Guide to the Mab Segrest Papers, 1889-2014 RL.01164
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Teaching, 1979-2014; 16 boxes
  - Connecticut College, 2001-2014
    - Connecticut College Gender & Women's Studies Department, undated (Box 128, Folder 11)
    - Connecticut College teaching, undated (Box 128, Folder 12, 13)
    - Connecticut College teaching, undated (Box 128, Folder 12, 13)
    - Correspondence with Connecticut College students, undated (Box 128, Folder 14)
    - New Orleans trip, undated (Box 129, Folder 1)
  - Duke University, 1979-2003
    - Duke House course on feminism, undated (Box 26, Folder 1)
    - Duke Cont'd Ed, undated (Box 26, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence, 1990-1992 (Box 26, Folder 3)
    - Duke Women's Studies, undated (Box 26, Folder 4)
    - Women's Studies, 2002-2003 (Box 26, Folder 5)
    - Elvis Presley, 1997 (Box 26, Folder 6)
    - Duke courses, 2001-2002 (Box 26, Folder 7)
    - Duke stationary, undated (Box 26, Folder 8)
    - Teaching: supportive material, 1994-2001 (Box 26, Folder 9)
    - Focus Program at Duke University, 2001 (Box 26, Folder 10)
    - Miscellaneous, 1980-1992 (Box 26, Folder 11)
    - John younger, 1999-2001 (Box 26, Folder 12)
    - Job, 1998-2001 (Box 26, Folder 13)
    - Duke Women's Studies, 2001 (Box 26, Folder 14)
    - Robertson Scholar, 2001 (Box 26, Folder 15)
    - Resume, 1979-1990 (Box 27, Folder 1)
    - University Scholars program, 2000-2001 (Box 27, Folder 2)
    - Associated Director Franklin, 2001 (Box 27, Folder 3)
    - Queer Southern Literature class, 2001 (Box 27, Folder 4)
    - Southern Literature course, 1992 (Box 27, Folder 5)
    - Power & Identity in Southern Literature course, 2001 (Box 27, Folder 6)
    - Social Problems course, 2002 (Box 28, Folder 1)
    - Feminist Theory and Method course, undated (Box 28, Folder 2)
    - Rereading Southern Lit. syllabus, 1990 (Box 28, Folder 3)
    - Reconstructing - Carson McCullers, 1992 (Box 129, Folder 2)
    - Syllabus for Southern Literature course at Duke, 1992 (Box 129, Folder 3)
    - Duke teaching, 1994 (Box 129, Folder 4)
    - Duke Queer Southern Literature course, 2001 (Box 129, Folder 5)
    - Carson McCullers, undated (Box 129, Folder 6, 7)
    - Duke evaluations, undated (Box 129, Folder 8)
  - Campbell University, 1980-1984
    - Campbell University, 1982-1983 (Box 29, Folder 1)
    - Lyricist, 1980-1983 (Box 29, Folder 2)
    - Lyricist, 1981-1984 (Box 29, Folder 3)
    - Lyricist report, 1981-1983 (Box 29, Folder 4)
    - Documents: CU, undated (Box 29, Folder 5)
    - Poetry instruction materials, undated (Box 29, Folder 6)
    - Pine Burr yearbooks, 1982-1983 (Box 30)
  - The University of North Carolina at Chapel Hill, 1995-2001
    - Southern Queer course, 1997-1998 (Box 31, Folder 1)
    - Southern/Queer UNC, 1995-1998 (Box 31, Folder 2)
    - Queer Southern Literature final papers, 2001 (Box 31, Folder 3, 4)
    - Southern/Gay Literature, 1997-1998 (Box 31, Folder 5)
    - UNC, 2001 (Box 31, Folder 6)
    - Application, 2000-2001 (Box 31, Folder 7)
    - UNC Queer S. Lit., 1998 (Box 31, Folder 8)
  - Various Institutions, 1994-2004
    - Course evaluation results, 1994-2002 (Box 80, Folder 6)
    - NEH fellowships, 1990 (Box 80, Folder 7)
    - Tulane Mellon Distinguished Professor, 2004 (Box 80, Folder 8)
    - Teaching portfolio, 2003 (Box 80, Folder 9)
    - Andrew W. Mellon Professor appointment from Tulane University, 2004 (Box 129, Folder 9)
    - Course evaluations, Tulane, 2004-2005 (Box 129, Folder 10)
    - Tulane, 2004 (Box 130, Folder 1, 2)
  - Migrant and Seasonal Farmworkers Association, 1983-1984
    - Ledger/notes, undated (Box 33, Folder 1)
    - Pamphlets/guides, undated (Box 33, Folder 2)
    - MSFA, 1983-1984 (Box 33, Folder 3)
    - Teaching aids, undated (Box 33, Folder 4)
  - Prison, circa 1980s
    - Prison/writing, undated (Box 33, Folder 5)
  - Personal Files, 1981-2001
    Conditions Governing Access
    This series is closed to research.
    - Planner, 1996 (Box 34, Folder 1, 2)
    - Daily planners, 1997-1998 (Box 34, Folder 3)
    - Daily planner, 1999 (Box 34, Folder 4)
    - Planning, undated (Box 34, Folder 5)
    - Royalties, 1986 (Box 123, Folder 1)
    - Budget Mab & Barb, 1987 (Box 123, Folder 2)
    - Doctors, 1988-1991 (Box 123, Folder 3)
    - Marty Nathan, undated (Box 123, Folder 4)
    - Notes, 1998 (Box 123, Folder 5)
    - Academic jobs, 2001 (Box 123, Folder 6)
    - Newsletters, postcards, and flyers, undated (Box 123, Folder 7)
    - Trans show, undated (Box 123, Folder 8)
    - Financial ledger, 2000-2002 (Box 123, Folder 9)
    - Journals, 1981 and 1994 (Box 123, Folder 10)
    - Clippings and ephemera, 1985 (Box 124, Folder 1)
    - Journal, notes, ephemera removed from 3-ring binder, 1981-1982 (Box 124, Folder 2-3)
    - Loose assorted notes, 1991-1992 (Box 124, Folder 4)
    - Journal with enclosed ephemera, 1987-1989 (Box 124, Folder 5)
    - Journal with enclosed ephemera, 1977 (Box 124, Folder 6-7)
    - Journal with enclosed ephemera, 1978-1979 (Box 124, Folder 8-9)
- Writings, 1938-2007; 39 boxes
  The Writings series is comprised of material documenting Dr. Segrest's published and unpublished work including books, articles, papers, and other works. The subseries are organized largest (most material) to smallest (last material).
  Publications represented in this series are Memoir of a Race Traitor, Born to Belonging, The Third Wave, My Mama's Dead Squirrel, Out in the South, Living in a House I Do Not Own, "What's Sex Got to Do With It, Y'all?" and "The Souls of White Folk",
  The Articles, Essays, and Book Reviews subseries contains an assortment of shorter writings (including drafts) by Dr. Segrest.
  The Manuscripts subseries is a collection of manuscripts labeled as "Rejected" or "Accepted." The Prelude was a publication at Huntingdon College, Dr. Segrest's alma mater. "Question of Equality" is a chapter of a companion volume to a PBS series about gay and lesbian rights. Dr. Segrest wrote one of four chapters in the book. "Outlook: National Gay and Lesbian Quarterly," was a serial publication. Dr. Segrest wrote a piece for the Winter 1989 edition that appears on pages 10-15.
  General
  Boxes 54 and 64 do not appear in this box sequence.
  - Memoir of a Race Traitor, 1985-1996
    - McKellar, Billy, 1985-1993 (Box 35, Folder 1)
    - Shelby murders: clippings, 1987-1988 (Box 35, Folder 2)
    - "Robeson County's Third-World Ills," Christian Century, 1988 (Box 35, Folder 3)
    - Robeson co., 1989 (Box 35, Folder 4)
    - Mab Segrest: Memoirs of a Race Traitor, 1990 (Box 35, Folder 5)
    - Draft of Race Traitor sent to my father, 1993 (Box 35, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence, 1993-1994 (Box 35, Folder 7)
    - Responses, 1993-1996 (Box 35, Folder 8-9)
    - Books Promo, 1994 (Box 35, Folder 10)
    - Jean Hardisty's review of Mab, 1994 (Box 35, Folder 11)
    - South End Press: Memoir of a Race Traitor, 1994 (Box 35, Folder 12)
    - Whose American History? By Barbara Smith, 1995 (Box 35, Folder 13)
    - Drafts and editorial notes, 1991-1994 (Box 36, Folder 1)
    - Research materials, 1985 (Box 36, Folder 2)
    - Publicity, 1994 (Box 36, Folder 3)
    - Chapter drafts, 1993 (Box 36, Folder 4-7)
    - Drafts and notes, 1993-1994 (Box 37, Folder 1-3)
    - Research, 1987-1988 (Box 37, Folder 4-5)
    - A Bridge, Not a Wedge, 1994 (Box 37, Folder 6)
    - Memoir of a Race Traitor drafts and editorial notes, 1988-1993 (Box 38)
    - On Being White and Other Lies, 1989-1990 (Box 39, Folder 1)
    - On Being White and Other Lies drafts, 1989-1991 (Box 39, Folder 2-4)
    - On Being White and Other Lies early draft, 1989-1990 (Box 39, Folder 5)
    - Edited draft of On Being White and Other Lies, 1992 (Box 39, Folder 6)
    - Race: latest I & II, 1991 (Box 40, Folder 1)
    - A Bridge, Not a Wedge, 1994 (Box 40, Folder 2)
    - Bad blood, 1993 (Box 40, Folder 3)
    - Novel: historical material, undated (Box 40, Folder 4)
    - Race research, 1989 and undated (Box 40, Folder 5)
    - Race III: in progress, 1989 and undated (Box 40, Folder 6)
    - Race essay, 1989-1990 (Box 40, Folder 7)
    - Drafts with edits, 1990-1993 (Box 41-42)
    - On Being White and Other Lies, 1993; undated (Box 43, Folder 1)
    - Clippings and research, 1989 (Box 43, Folder 2)
    - Handwritten interview transcript, Statesville KKK incident, undated (Box 43, Folder 3)
    - Clippings, 1986-1989 (Box 43, Folder 4)
    - Robeson research, 1987-1991 (Box 43, Folder 5-7)
    - Chapter drafts with edits, 1993 (Box 43, Folder 8-9)
    - Memoirs of a Race Traitor, Carl, Mama's funeral, 1992 (Box 131, Folder 1)
    - New Race Traitor essay, undated (Box 131, Folder 2)
  - Born to Belonging, 1990-2005
    - Born to Belonging, 1998 (Box 44, Folder 1-2)
    - Belonging, 2001-2002 (Box 44, Folder 3)
    - Born to Belonging cover, 2002 (Box 44, Folder 4)
    - Born to Belonging draft, undated (Box 44, Folder 5-8)
    - Born to Belonging draft, undated (Box 45-46, Folder 1-6)
    - Born to Belonging notes, 2002 (Box 63, Folder 6)
    - Whiteness and Privilege essay, 1996 (Box 63, Folder 7)
    - Ch. 2 Atlanta, 1990-1995 (Box 48, Folder 1)
    - Olympics Out of Cobb, 1991-1995 (Box 48, Folder 2)
    - Atlanta, 1992-2001 (Box 48, Folder 3)
    - Atlanta/Coke, 1996 (Box 48, Folder 4)
    - Independent Weekly, 1996 (Box 48, Folder 5)
    - Olympics, 1996 (Box 48, Folder 6)
    - Beijing, 1995 (Box 49, Folder 1, 2, 3)
    - Beijing - letter of acceptance, 1995 (Box 49, Folder 4)
    - Beijing planning, 1995 (Box 49, Folder 5)
    - Beijing: plenary, 1995 (Box 49, Folder 6)
    - CCR, 1995-1996 (Box 49, Folder 7)
    - China/Belonging, 1995-1999 (Box 49, Folder 8)
    - China document/Belonging, 1995-2001 (Box 49, Folder 9)
    - Forum on Women Beijing, 1995 (Box 49, Folder 10)
    - Health Day, 1995 (Box 50, Folder 1)
    - Laura Flanders, 1995 (Box 50, Folder 2)
    - News and views, 1995 (Box 50, Folder 3)
    - WEDO, 1995 (Box 50, Folder 4)
    - Common ground - Beijing, 1996 (Box 50, Folder 5)
    - Durham women: making change happen, 1996 (Box 50, Folder 6)
    - Forum for the Future, 1996 (Box 50, Folder 7)
    - Beijing essay, 2000 (Box 50, Folder 8)
    - Papers and emails, 2001 (Box 50, Folder 9)
    - Beijing report, undated (Box 50, Folder 10)
    - Equality for Chinese women, undated (Box 50, Folder 11)
    - Les* Beijing, undated (Box 50, Folder 12)
    - African health, 1995-2001 (Box 51, Folder 1)
    - Durban, 1996-2001 (Box 51, Folder 2)
    - Africa/Belonging, 1997-2001 (Box 51, Folder 3)
    - Assembly handbook, 1997-2001 (Box 51, Folder 4)
    - South Africa/GLBT, 1997-1999 (Box 51, Folder 5)
    - Africa, 1998-2001 (Box 51, Folder 6)
    - GLBT, 1998-1999 (Box 51, Folder 7)
    - Honolulu, 1997 (Box 52, Folder 1)
    - Hawaiian sovereignty/gay marriage, 1998 (Box 52, Folder 2)
    - Memphis, undated (Box 52, Folder 3)
    - Epilogue - Belonging, 1998-2001 (Box 52, Folder 4)
    - U.N. documents, 1995 (Box 52, Folder 5)
    - China, undated (Box 52, Folder 6, 7)
    - Hawaii, undated (Box 52, Folder 8)
    - Hawaii draft & Hawaii chapter/B2B, undated (Box 52, Folder 9)
    - WCC Harare assembly programme, 1998 (Box 52, Folder 10)
    - Standing in Solidarity with the Gay and Lesbian Community in Zimbabwe, undated (Box 52, Folder 11)
    - Hawaii, 1997 (Box 53, Folder 1)
    - Hawaii, undated (Box 53, Folder 2)
    - Hawaiian Sovereignty draft, undated (Box 53, Folder 3)
    - Misc., 1995 (Box 53, Folder 4)
    - China trip, 2005 (Box 122, Folder 1)
    - Born to Belonging feedback from Adrienne Rich, 2002 (Box 131, Folder 4)
    - Beijing prep, NGO forum, 1995 (Box 131, Folder 3)
  - Third Wave, 1988-1992
    This became the book Sing, Whisper, Shout, Pray: Feminist Visions for a Just World
    - Letter: K. Kantrowitz, 1989 (Box 55, Folder 1)
    - Notes on "Race" for Third Wave, 1989 (Box 55, Folder 2)
    - Third Wave: meeting notes & memos, 1988-1991 (Box 55, Folder 3)
    - Third Wave: notes on content current databases, 1989-1990 (Box 55, Folder 4)
    - Third Wave, 1991-1992 (Box 55, Folder 5)
    - Third Wave: miscellaneous correspondence, 1988-1990 (Box 55, Folder 6)
    - Third Wave: latest intro, undated (Box 56, Folder 1)
    - Third Wave: most current, undated (Box 56, Folder 2)
    - Third Wave, 1989 (Box 56, Folder 3)
    - Astraea grant proposal, 1991 (Box 131, Folder 5)
  - My Mama's Dead Squirrel, 1985-1998
    - Book: My Mama's Dead Squirrel, 1985 (Box 57)
    - Firebrand/Mama, 1985-1988 (Box 57, Folder 1)
    - Squirrel reviews, 1985-1991 (Box 57, Folder 2)
    - Book reviews, 1986-1987 (Box 57, Folder 3)
    - Book royalties, 1994-1998 (Box 57, Folder 4)
    - My Mama's Dead Squirrel drafts, undated (Box 57, Folder 5)
  - Lines I Dare To Write, 1981-2000
    - Lines I Dare: draft, 1981 (Box 58, Folder 1)
    - Lines I Dare: drafts, 1981-1985 (Box 58, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence with Kathleen Aguero, including drafts, 1983 (Box 58, Folder 3)
    - Lines I Dare: drafts, 1988 (Box 58, Folder 4)
    - Out in the South, 2000 (Box 58, Folder 5)
  - Living in a House I Do Not Own, 1977-1987
    - Living in a House cover, misc, 1977 (Box 59, Folder 1)
    - Crossing account, 1982-1984 (Box 59, Folder 2)
    - Living in a House: reviews, 1982 (Box 59, Folder 3)
    - Inland, 1986-1987 (Box 59, Folder 4)
    - Living in a House I Do Not Own announcement, undated (Box 59, Folder 5)
    - Mab's book, 1982 (Box 59, Folder 6)
  - Mac Lee, 1981-2000
    - American Literature: Mac Lee, 1981-1992 (Box 60, Folder 1)
    - Mac Lee, 1982-1989 (Box 60, Folder 2)
    - Rev. Lee, 1985 (Box 60, Folder 3)
    - Mac Lee: VA library, 1989-2000 (Box 60, Folder 4)
    - Reconstruction or Deconstruction: Mack Lee, 1989 (Box 60, Folder 5-6)
    - Articles quoted in Mac Lee, undated (Box 60, Folder 7)
    - Letters & memoirs, undated (Box 60, Folder 8)
    - Reviews, undated (Box 60, Folder 9)
    - Mac Lee draft, 1989 (Box 131, Folder 6)
  - Poetry, 1970-1991
    - Poems, finished/uncollected, circa 1970s (Box 61, Folder 1)
    - Early poems: Gregson St. & University Drive, 1976 (Box 61, Folder 2)
    - Poems about my mother, 1978-1988 (Box 61, Folder 3)
    - Pagoda poetry workshop with Adrienne Rich, 1980-1982 (Box 61, Folder 4)
    - Red Bass, 1986 (Box 61, Folder 5)
    - Assorted poetry, 1991 (Box 61, Folder 6)
    - Yellowstone poems, 1991 (Box 61, Folder 7)
    - Poems, undated (Box 61, Folder 8)
    - Red Bass, undated (Box 61, Folder 9)
      - Sinister Wisdom, 1981 (Box 61, Folder 10)
    - Syrup Making, framed with photo, 1977 (Box 62)
  - Lillian Smith, 1993-1994
    - Lillian Smith, 1993-1994 (Box 63, Folder 1)
  - What's Sex Got to Do With It, Y'all?, 1997-1999
    - What's Sex Got To Do With It ... drafts, etc., 1997 (Box 63, Folder 2-5)
    - "What's Sex Got to Do With It, Y'all?", 1999 (Box 63, Folder 8)
    - "What's Sex Got to Do With It, Y'all?" draft, undated (Box 63, Folder 9)
  - The Souls of White Folk, 1988-1997
    - Setting the World in Balance, 1988 (Box 65, Folder 1)
    - Souls of White Folk, 1996-1998 (Box 65, Folder 2)
    - "The Souls of White Folks", 1996-1997 (Box 65, Folder 3)
    - The Souls of White Folks draft, undated (Box 65, Folder 4)
  - Articles, Essays, & Book Reviews, 1977-2007
    - Feminism article, 1977-1983 (Box 66, Folder 1)
    - Conversations with Barbara Deming: reprinted in Reweaving, 1979-1982 (Box 66, Folder 2)
    - Confessions of a Closet Baptist, 1981-1983 (Box 66, Folder 3)
    - Fatal Flowers: review, 1981 (Box 66, Folder 4)
    - Mama, Granny, Carrie Bell, 1981-1982 (Box 66, Folder 5)
    - Mama, Granny, Carrie Bell drafts, 1981-1983 (Box 66, Folder 6)
    - Conversations with Barbara Deming, 1985-1987 (Box 66, Folder 7)
    - Recall: advocate article, 1986 (Box 66, Folder 8)
    - Stonewall dinner speech, DM Herald articles on recall campaign, 1986 (Box 66, Folder 9)
    - Gay Pride, the front page, 1987 (Box 66, Folder 10)
    - Christian Century: Robeson piece, 1988 (Box 66, Folder 11)
    - In These Times reviews, 1989 (Box 66, Folder 12)
    - My reviews, 1989 (Box 66, Folder 13)
    - Crime Against Nature review, 1990 (Box 66, Folder 14)
    - AM Forum gay article, 1991 (Box 66, Folder 15)
    - Bridges, 1991-1992 (Box 66, Folder 16)
    - Copies of articles, 1993-1996 (Box 66, Folder 17)
    - Article, 1994-1995 (Box 66, Folder 18)
    - Bell Hooks review, 1995 (Box 66, Folder 19)
    - Faxes, 1995 (Box 66, Folder 20)
    - Lesbian Herstory Archives, News 5, 1979 (Box 66, Folder 22)
    - Waiting for Hillary, 1995 (Box 66, Folder 21)
    - Emails, articles, 1996-2001 (Box 67, Folder 1)
    - Thomas Merton Center, 1996 (Box 67, Folder 2)
    - Confessions of a Closet Baptist, 1999 (Box 67, Folder 3)
    - Annie, Mama, Carl, undated (Box 67, Folder 4)
    - Articles, undated (Box 67, Folder 5)
    - Article in Bridges, edited by Adrienne Rich, undated (Box 67, Folder 6)
    - Articles and drafts, undated (Box 67, Folder 7)
    - Assorted drafts, undated (Box 67, Folder 8)
    - Body is Your Subconscious Mind, undated (Box 67, Folder 9)
    - Carl, an AIDS memoir, undated (Box 67, Folder 10)
    - Delicate Conversations, undated (Box 67, Folder 11)
    - Elvis, undated (Box 67, Folder 12)
    - Greensboro Independent article, undated (Box 67, Folder 13)
    - Hurdle Mills drafts, undated (Box 67, Folder 14)
    - Indy excerpt, undated (Box 67, Folder 15)
    - MAC3: new comp, undated (Box 68, Folder 1)
    - Miscellaneous, undated (Box 68, Folder 2)
    - New book, undated (Box 68, Folder 3)
    - Notes and drafts, undated (Box 68, Folder 4)
    - Notepad, undated (Box 68, Folder 5)
    - Papers and drafts, undated (Box 68, Folder 6)
    - Southern women writing, undated (Box 68, Folder 7)
    - "Queer Like Me" Independent cover, 1998 (Box 68, Folder 8)
    - Which Colonial State?, 2007 (Box 68, Folder 9)
    - White Feminists in a White Supremacist Culture, undated (Box 68, Folder 10)
    - Mystery/plot, undated (Box 68, Folder 11)
    - The Reader's Companion to US Women's History, undated (Box 68, Folder 12)
    - Down South, Up South, and Out South, undated (Box 68, Folder 13)
    - Duke papers, undated (Box 68, Folder 14)
    - Segrest email regarding "Blurbs", 2002 (Box 68, Folder 15)
    - To Misceginate the Canon, undated (Box 69, Folder 1)
    - Pages/novel draft, undated (Box 69, Folder 2)
    - Novel draft, undated (Box 69, Folder 3)
    - Draft?, undated (Box 69, Folder 4)
    - Novel draft pages, undated (Box 69, Folder 5)
    - Novel draft?, undated (Box 69, Folder 6)
    - Racism anthology, undated (Box 69, Folder 7)
    - Novel printout, undated (Box 69, Folder 8)
    - Drag You Off to Milledgeville, undated (Box 69, Folder 9)
    - Notecards, undated (Box 70)
    - Segrest interviewed by Jean Hardistry, 1994 (Box 46, Folder 4)
    - Ideologies of Slavery/Ideologies of Freedom: An Oppositional History of Southern Literature (Proposal), 1991 (Box 131, Folder 7)
    - Flannery O'Connor notes, 1994 (Box 131, Folder 8)
    - Autobiography and liberation, undated (Box 131, Folder 9)
    - History/theory questions for book, undated (Box 131, Folder 10)
    - Lit Crit notes, undated (Box 131, Folder 11)
    - To Misceginate the Canon, undated (Box 131, Folder 12)
    - Rough draft, undated (Box 131, Folder 13)
  - Manuscripts: Accepted/Rejected, 1982-1990
    This series closed to research.
    - Accepted, 1988-1990 (Box 71, Folder 1, 2, 3)
    - Accepted provisionally, 1982-1990 (Box 71, Folder 4)
    - Rejected, undated (Box 71, Folder 5, 6)
    - Rejected, undated (Box 72, Folder 1, 2, 3, 4)
  - The Prelude, 1938-1970
    - Prelude, volume 10, number 2, 1938 (Box 73)
    - The Prelude, volume 40, number 1, 1968 (Box 73)
    - The Prelude, volume 40, number 2, 1969 (Box 73)
    - The Prelude, volume 40, number 3, 1969 (Box 73)
    - The Prelude, volume 41, number 2, 1970 (Box 73)
    - The Prelude, volume 41, number 3, 1970 (Box 73)
    - The Prelude, volume 42, undated (Box 73)
    - The Prelude, volume 43, undated (Box 73)
    - The Prelude, 1970 (Box 73)
    - The Prelude, 1967 (Box 73)
    - The Prelude, 1968 (Box 73)
    - The Prelude, 1969 (Box 73)
  - Question of Equality, 1994-1995
    - Matt Foreman, 1994 (Box 74, Folder 1)
    - Miscellaneous, undated (Box 74, Folder 2)
    - Notes & chapter drafts, undated (Box 74, Folder 3)
    - Question of Equality correspondence, 1994 (Box 74, Folder 4)
    - Question of Equality draft, 1994 (Box 74, Folder 5)
    - Question of Equality draft, sent to David Deitcher, 1994 (Box 74, Folder 6)
    - Testing the Limits & Tongues Untied, 1994 (Box 74, Folder 7)
    - The Question of Equality, 1995 (Box 74, Folder 8)
  - National Gay and Lesbian Task Force, 1989
    - Outlook: National Lesbian & Gay Quarterly, 1989 (Box 74, Folder 9-10)
- Activism, 1969-2014; 30 boxes
  The subseries contained in the Activism series are arranged in descending order by amount of material, then chronologically where possible within each organizational subseries.
  Dr. Segrest helped to form NCARRV (North Carolinians Against Racist and Religious Violence) in 1985 with Christina Davis-McCoy. The group focused on anti-Klan activity in the state.
  In the mid-1990s, Dr. Segrest was involved with the North Carolina Coalition for Gay and Lesbian Equality (NCGLE).
  WomonWrites is a retreat for female authors founded in 1979. Dr. Segrest was one of the chief organizers.
  The Our South subseries contains materials related to Dr. Segrest's involvement in the group in the 1980s.
  From its creation in 1969 until it disbanded in 1983, Segrest participated in the southern feminist writing collective Feminary working to produce the journal of the same name.
  Dr. Segrest was on the board (1986-1997) of the Center for Democratic Renewal, which was founded in 1979 as the National Anti-Klan Network by C.T. Vivian and Anne Braden.
  The National Women's Studies Association and the Southeastern Women's Studies Association subseries contain materials related to Dr. Segrest's work with those organizations.
  Dr. Segrest was Coordinator (1992-2000) of the Urban Rural Mission, part of the World Council of Churches.
  The Various Groups subseries reflect Dr. Segrest's involvement with many social justice and feminist causes throughout the course of her career.
  The Conferences and Speeches subseries contains materials related to guest lectures, keynote addresses, and speeches that Dr. Segrest has given around the country, as well as information about conferences that she has attended (and in some cases helped to organize).
  - North Carolinians Against Racist and Religious Violence (NCARRV), 1985-1993
    - NCARRV, 1985-1988 (Box 76, Folder 1)
    - NCARRV mailings, fliers, etc., 1985-1991 (Box 76, Folder 2)
    - NCARRV newsletters, pix of White Patriots, 1985-1988 (Box 76, Folder 3)
    - NCARRV/Shelby murders, 1985-1989 (Box 76, Folder 4)
    - Miscellaneous, 1986-1988 (Box 76, Folder 5)
    - NCARRV annual reports, 1986-1990 (Box 76, Folder 6)
    - NCARRV newsletters & publications, 1986-1990 (Box 76, Folder 7)
    - NCARRV, 1987-1993 (Box 76, Folder 8)
    - NCARRV board, 1987 (Box 76, Folder 9)
    - NCARRV long-term planning, 1987-1989 (Box 76, Folder 10)
    - NCARRV workplan, 1988 (Box 77, Folder 1)
    - NCARRV board, 1989 (Box 77, Folder 2)
    - NCARRV reports: annual, 1989-1990 (Box 77, Folder 3)
    - NCARRV: Mab's notes $, 1989-1990 (Box 77, Folder 4)
    - NCARRV staff meetings, 1989 (Box 77, Folder 5)
    - NCARRV board, 1990 (Box 77, Folder 6)
    - NCARRV report, 1990 (Box 77, Folder 7)
    - Resignation from NCARRV, 1990 (Box 77, Folder 8)
    - NCARRV staff meetings, workplans, 1990 (Box 77, Folder 9)
    - Segrest time sheets, 1990 (Box 77, Folder 10)
    - Breaking the Cycle of Bigotry: NCARRV youth leadership packet, undated (Box 77, Folder 11, 12)
    - Miscellaneous, undated (Box 77, Folder 13)